Finding Aid of the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Office of the Director Records, 1885-2014
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1885-2014, UWM Archival Collection 10; 28.6 cubic ft. (49 boxes, including 15 audio reels, 16 audio cassettes, and 23 videocassettes) 1 oversize folder
  - Reference Manual, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Regents Dinner, Exhibit, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 60)
  - Religion and Politics, Jeansonne, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 61)
  - Remington Rand, 1933-1960 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Remodel, 1971-1974 (Box 42, Folder 62)
  - Reorganization
    - 1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 1985 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Report Re: Bookcases, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Resource Planning Document, 1998-1999 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Reuss, Henry S., 1955-1961 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Richard Abel & Company, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Robillard, French Exhibit, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 63)
  - Romani, John H., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Roosevelt Collection, 1978-1980 (Box 42, Folder 64)
  - Roosevelt, FDR Night, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 65)
  - Roselle's First Friday, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 66)
  - Rosenblum, Marty, Benefit, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 67)
  - Salaries
    - 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - 1991-1996 (Box 32, Folder 43)
  - Sandburg Anniversary
    - 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - 1978 March 10, Audio reel (¼ in., 7 ½ ips) (Box 13, Audio 6)
  - Schatzman, Erna, Interview with Linda Scott, 29 November 1984, Audio cassette (Box 27, Audio 9)
  - Schenck, Quentin F., 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Schick, Frank G., 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Science Complex Collection Equipment, 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 68)
  - Schlacks, Charles, Jr., 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - School of Architecture, 1969-1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - School of Education, 1975-1993 (Box 32, Folder 44)
  - School of Library and Information Science
    - 1948-1975 (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
    - Resource Center, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - School of Nursing, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Schroeter Collection, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 69)
  - Science Complex Collection, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Science Complex Library, 1962-1971 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Sculpture in the Library Court, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Sculpture, Milwaukee Dedication, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 45)
  - Search and Screen Committee, Curator, American Geographical Society Collection, 1993-1994 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of the Faculty, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Serial Review Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Serials, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Serials Cancellations
    - 1975 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - 1982 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - 1993 (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
  - Serials Merge Task Team, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Serials Review
    - 1979-1984 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Seventeenth Century Research Collection, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Seventeenth Century Research Lectures, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 31)
  - Shabad Collection, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 70)
  - Shakespeare
    - 1994 (Box 42, Folder 71)
    - 2001 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Shape and Color of Research, 2002 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Sher Lecture, Paul Wexler, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 72)
  - Siegel Program, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 73)
  - Signs, 1971-1973 (Box 42, Folder 74)
  - Skzypek, Stanislaw, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Slichter Collection of Civil War Materials, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Slides
    - AGS and Preservation, undated (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Library and other UWM Buildings, 1986-1988 (Box 32, Folder 47)
    - Library Construction, Stage 3, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 48)
    - Library Director Roselle, undated (Box 32, Folder 49)
    - Mercata Engraving, Pre-preservation, undated (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Overcrowded Conditions, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 51)
    - Rare Book Deterioration, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 52)
  - Slovenia Ethnomusicological Project, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 75)
  - Slovenian Music Collection, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 76)
  - Smithsonian Event, 1983 (Box 42, Folder 77)
  - Snoopervisors' Weekly Review, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Snyder, Milwaukee Art Museum, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 78)
  - Solochek Gift, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 79)
  - Solon, John, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Sorkin, Leonard, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Sorrin, Saul, Projects, 1988-1989 (Box 42, Folder 80)
  - Special Collections, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Speedskating Program, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 81)
  - Spyers-Duran, Peter, 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Staff Association Activities
    - 1974-1984 (Box 10, Folder 26-28)
    - Annual Meetings, 1963-1983 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Bylaws, 1963-1985 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Cookbook, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Executive Committee
      - Memos, 1963-1987 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - Minutes, 1963-1986 (Box 10, Folder 33-34)
    - Lounge Committee, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Membership Lists, 1972-1982 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Party Committee, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Reports, 1955-1984 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Staff Room Committee, 1956-1965 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Treasurer, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Staff Development Committee Report, 1991-1992 (Box 32, Folder 53)
  - Staff Meetings, 1945-1961, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Staff Memos
    - 1944-1960 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - 1961-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - 1983-1987 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Staff Newsletter
    - 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 1991-2000 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Stage II
    - Browsing Room, 1973-1974 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Completion Date, 1974-1975 (Box 49, Folder 33)
  - State Employees Strike, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Statistical Reports
    - 1924-1944 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - 1963-1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Statistical Summaries, 1986-1989 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Stromberg, Roland, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Student Data Base Consortium, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Student Help, 1957-1961 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Student Hours, 1990-1992 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Student Training Manual, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Summer Sessions, 1948-1961 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Tarnoff, Lawrence R., 1968 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Task Force on Civil Service Employment, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Technical Services, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Technical Services Manual, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Telecommunications Task Force
    - 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
    - Centrex Analysis, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Final Report, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 23-24)
    - Open Hearings, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 26-27)
    - Subcommittees, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Text-Book Library Withdrawal Book, undated (Box 22)
  - Textbooks, 1947-1956 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Theses, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Thesis and Dissertation Study Committee, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Tips on Using the Library, 1964-1968 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Title IX, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Training School Library Accession Books, 1931-1945 (Box 22)
  - 20th Anniversary of the Transfer of the AGSL to UWM, 1998, 1 Videocassette (VHS) (Box 44, Video 2)
  - 20th Century Photograph Program, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 82)
  - Twenty-Four Hour Library, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - U.S. Air Force Still Photos Collection, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Superintendent of Documents, 1949-1964 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - University Art Museum, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - The University Library and the Arts, Symposium, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - University Library Committee
    - 1960 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - 1971-1981 (Box 11, Folder 36-40)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - 1984-1993 (Box 42, Folder 83-92)
    - 1988 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 43, Folder 1-10)
    - Budget Data, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - University New Library Orientation Committee, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - University of California, 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - University of Wisconsin Library Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - University of Wisconsin Library Council, 1965-1969 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - University of Wisconsin-Madison, Memorial Library, 1957-1970 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - University of Wisconsin System Library Planning Study, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - University of Wisconsin-Waukesha, 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - University Student Government, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - UW System University/Industry Cooperation, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - UWM Buildings: Some Pertinent Facts, 1968-1977 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - UWM Centennial, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - UWM Foundation, 1986-1993 (Box 32, Folder 54-55)
  - UW-M Library News, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Valuation of Library Collection, 1979-1984 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Vending Machines, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Vevier, Charles, 1962-1967 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Vice Chancellor Staff Meetings, 1996-1997 (Box 32, Folder 56)
  - Videotape Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Vizenor Program, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Vogel Talk, Native American Week, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Voice of Turtle Hannukah/Christmas Concert, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Wallis Lecture, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Wallis Talks, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Walters, William L., 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Waste Receptacles, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Watson-Boone, Peter, Interview on WUWM, 1993, Audio cassette (Box 27, Audio 14)
  - Weil, Herman, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Weinberg Collection, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Weinberg, Dudley, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 2-23)
  - Weinshel, Howard, Donations, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 34)
  - "Wies Polska Roku 1934", 1987 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - William Morris Lecture, 1976, Audio reel (¼ in., 7 ½ ips) (Box 13, Audio 7)
  - Wisconsin Architectural Archives, 1985-1988 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Wisconsin Council for Geographic Education Meeting Program, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction, 1954-1959 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Wisconsin Free Library Commission, 1955-1961 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Wisconsin Society for Jewish Learning, 1962-1970 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Wisconsin Society of the Children of the American Revolution, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Witte Collection, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Woodmansee, Mrs. Webster, 1975-1986 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - World Anthropology Lecture, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - World's Fairs Lecture, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Xeroxing, 1963-1965 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Year 2000 Master Plan Committee, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Additions, 1990-1998, Accession 1998-055; 1 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions largely consisting of memos, budget planning files, and NLS/NOTIS files, dating from 1990 to 1998.
- Personnel Files, closed before 2005, Accession 1999-059; .2 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of personnel files closed before 2005.
- Additions, 1969-2001, Accession 2005-007; 2.4 cubic ft. (3 boxes); Additions containing materials concerning the establishment of the Fromkin Memorial Collection, Fromkin lecture applications and proposals, and correspondence concerning Fromkin book. Files date from 1969 to 2001.
- Additions, 1982-2000, Accession 2006-016; 1 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions including Friends records, holiday cards, affirmative action evaluation, exhibits and program files, Staff Development Committee, and Staff Advisory Council files, dating from 1982 to 2000.
- Administrative Files, 1980-2004, Accession 2006-070; 41 cubic ft. (41 boxes); Additions of administrative files, largely dating from 1980 to 2004.
- Minutes, 1994-2001, Accession 2007-007; .4 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of minutes for the Friends, Staff Advisory Council, and the University Library Committee. Also includes a file pertaining to the library strategic plan. Files date from 1994 to 2001.
- Photographs and Ephemera, 1963-2007, Accession 2009-014; 4 cubic ft. (4 boxes); Additions of photographs and ephemera dating from 1963 to 2007. Includes pamphlets and mailings advertising library events, and a few early architectural drawings of Stage I of the library.
- Miscellaneous Files, 1970-1998, Accession 2009-023; 1 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of miscellaneous files, dating from 1970 to 1998. Includes files on Fromkin and Hardie gifts (with associated agreements and correspondence), some files on the Phase III building project, and some publicity materials. Also included are numerous unique Friends of the Library newsletters, as well as photographs of events between 1980 and 1998.
- Artwork, 2007, Accession 2009-024; 1 oversize folder; Additions of Daniel Soref Learning Commons artwork and an oversize exterior photo of the library. Materials are from 2007 and undated.
- Administrative Files, 1991-2008, Accession 2010-045; 1.8 cubic ft. (3 boxes); Additions of administrative files largely dating from 1991 to 2008.
- Administrative Files, 1988-2005, Accession 2011-008; 1 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of administrative files, including materials focusing on planning and budget, dating from 1988 to 2005.
- Additions, 1976-1990, Accession 2011-033; .4 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of miscellaneous AGSL-related publications. Also includes AGSL contracts and founding documents. Materials date from 1976 to 1990.
- Miscellaneous Materials, 1984-2009, Accession 2012-022; 1 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of miscellaneous materials, including planning documents, staff newsletters, chrono files, remodeling, and user survey files.
- Emails, 1997-2003, Accession 2012-044; 2693 digital text files (17 MB); Additions of emails from Peter Watson-Boone dating from 1997 to 2003. Includes correspondence relating to several functions of Watson-Boone's tenure as Library Director, including communication with library and campus units and correspondence relating to his participation in CUWL. Some materials also relate to personnel matters and are restricted.
- Tapes, 1979, Accession 2013-010; 2 C-type videotapes and 2 1-inch videotapes; Additions of video of the dedication of the Golda Meir Library in 1979.
- Fromkin Lecture Series, 1969-2002, Accession 2015-030; .8 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Additions of records pertaining to the Fromkin lecture series, dating from 1969 to 2002. Includes information about the establishment of the Fromkin collection, correspondence, proposals, copies of lectures, guides to sources in the Fromkin collection and the Archives, as well as some materials pertaining to the Quest for Social Justice, volumes I and II.